<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheWalrus</title>
    <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TheWalrus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:45:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thewalr.us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Esp8266 as an Iot Endpoint With Encrypted Mqtt Transport</title>
      <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/2019/03/27/using-esp8266-as-an-iot-endpoint-with-encrypted-mqtt-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:45:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thewalr.us/2019/03/27/using-esp8266-as-an-iot-endpoint-with-encrypted-mqtt-transport/</guid>
      <description>Using ESP8266 as an IoT Endpoint with Encrypted MQTT Transport A while back, I purchased a few SparkFun Thing Dev boards (featuring the venerable ESP8266 WiFi chipset) and SparkFun Beefcake Relays with a plan to use them in a cloud-free IoT setup. After some investigation, I settled on using the MQTT protocol as a lightweight way to send and receive messages between my Linux server and any number of IoT endpoints throughout my house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Zero W Simultaneous AP and Managed Mode Wifi</title>
      <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/2017/09/26/raspberry-pi-zero-w-simultaneous-ap-and-managed-mode-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:47:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thewalr.us/2017/09/26/raspberry-pi-zero-w-simultaneous-ap-and-managed-mode-wifi/</guid>
      <description>Enabling Simultaneous AP and Managed Mode WiFi on Raspberry Pi Zero W (Raspbian Stretch) I recently purchased a pair of Raspberry Pi Zero W boards, and plan to use them for some home automation / IoT-type work. One of my requirements is that the WiFi on this board be able to run as both a &amp;ldquo;managed&amp;rdquo; device (also known as &amp;ldquo;client&amp;rdquo; mode) and as an access point, preferrably at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/2016/05/26/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 12:04:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thewalr.us/2016/05/26/hello/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s with TheWalrus? This one&amp;rsquo;s easy. I was looking for interesting words that end with &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; that could be purchased as cheap domain names. I picked up a few and so far have only maintained TheWalrus and TheCactus. I have no personal attachment to either one yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can retroactively drum something up if I can dedicate some time to this blog.
What&amp;rsquo;s with this blog? Ever since &amp;ndash; ohh&amp;hellip; &amp;ndash; high school, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to keep an online journal of sorts, before the word &amp;lsquo;Blog&amp;rsquo; was a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>