<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello on TheWalrus</title>
    <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/tags/hello/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello on TheWalrus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 12:04:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.thewalr.us/tags/hello/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://blog.thewalr.us/2016/05/26/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 12:04:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.thewalr.us/2016/05/26/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-with-thewalrus&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s with TheWalrus?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;rsquo;s easy. I was looking for interesting words that end with &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; that could be purchased as cheap domain names. I picked up a few and so far have only maintained &lt;a href=&#34;https://thewalr.us&#34;&gt;TheWalrus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://thecact.us&#34;&gt;TheCactus&lt;/a&gt;. I have no personal attachment to either one yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can retroactively drum something up if I can dedicate some time to this blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-with-this-blog&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s with this blog?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since &amp;ndash; ohh&amp;hellip; &amp;ndash; high school, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to keep an online journal of sorts, before the word &amp;lsquo;Blog&amp;rsquo; was a thing.  I&amp;rsquo;ve made several attempts at doing it, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to either hand-code, self-host, or otherwise have total control of the whole thing. I have a tendency to start things, work on them until they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;good enough,&amp;rdquo; and then never really finish them up. Naturally, this has led to a lot of half-hearted starts at creating my own website which inevitably fall to the wayside once work, family, and real life take center stage.  Finally, I gave in and decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that getting past this intial hurdle will allow me to finally concentrate on the content rather thant he delivery mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
